Joshua Delsman

1250 South Miami Avenue, #3005, Miami, Florida 33130 jdelsman@voxxit.com

PERSONAL PROFILE

Highly qualified, senior-level web application developer with over nine years of management and development experience in the Internet service and media industries. Effective leader focused on the simplicity, accessibility and ease of use of software. Talent for reversing negative sales trends, creating beautiful, exciting user experiences, and maximizing profit and automation in businesses both large and small. Qualified and highly recommended expert in emerging Ruby and Javascript technologies.

EDUCATION

Florida Atlantic University - Boca Raton, FL

Partial Computer Science (B.S.) degree - 2008 to 2009

Suffolk University - Boston, MA

Partial Business & Marketing (B.S.) degree - 2007 to 2008

William T. McFatter Technical Center - Davie, FL

New Media/Graphic Arts certificate - 2003 to 2007

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer, Senzari Miami, FL - 2011 to Current

Helped launch Senzari in late 2011 in multiple worldwide markets. Developed a 3rd party widget which allows users of different sites to listen to music as they browse. Managed the user experience and frontend technologies of the site, including Backbone. JS and RIA technologies.

Senior Software Engineer, Critical Mention New York, NY - 2010 to 2011

Headed up projects to upgrade Rails-based software projects to Rails 3. Abstracted functionality from a number of projects and developed a separate API for third-parties to utilize using widgets. Developed an OAuth v2 authorization server from IETF draft specification, and developed a high-level JavaScript API which widgets used to communicate around same-domain policy limitations.

Software Development Head, Ultraspeed London, UK - 2009 to 2010

Designed and developed an enterprise billing/customer management and ordering platform using Ruby on Rails, incorporating over ten different third-party APIs using SOAP and RESTful XML and JSON. Worked with large domain name and SSL certificate providers to assist with their own API development to help meet our needs better. Wrote open-source EPP Ruby gem to interface with domain name registries supporting the standard EPP protocol; used in Ultraspeed operations, and by other companies publicly. Gave successful talks at industry events on the power of Ruby on Rails web development, and how to succeed using it.

Sr. Web Developer, Destination Rewards Boca Raton, FL - 2008 to 2009

Worked with Fortune 100 companies to develop incentive/royalty platforms according to their business model, incorporating their branding. Coordinated team of developers to handle front-end tasks on a daily basis, and spearheaded operations which included full-scale enterprise design and Ruby on Rails application development. Frequently trained employees and lead interactive workshops on the best design & development methodologies and best practices.

Systems Administrator, Lunarpages Los Angeles, CA - 2006-2008

Responsible for assisting in monitoring and administration of over 1,000 shared and dedicated servers at a time, concurrently serving over one million customers. Took part in developing Bash and Ruby scripts to assist with repetative administrative tasks. Frequently consulted with enterprise clients for scaling their web presence with clustered environments.

Owner, Voxxit, Inc. Miami, FL - 2003 to 2008

Responsible for daily operations, including complete wireframing, web design, development, implementation, and quality assurance/testing. Additionally, responsibilities included business development, sales and finance. Bootstrapped many successful Ruby on Rails and JavaScript projects, both desktop and mobile, such as myhurricane.net.

"Josh is an extremely capable individual who's personal drive and motivation to provide simple, well thought out solutions and systems for complex and integral projects have been a key factor to the continuing and future success of the Ultraspeed Group. It's rare to see such attention to detail and pride in one's work in someone of his age. I'm positively refreshed by his attitude to take an active interest in other areas of the business in implementing his development projects."

Namuli Katumba Head of Business Development Ultraspeed

"Josh is a first-rate developer. He has a passion for doing it the right way, combined with a blazing output rate. He also does a very good job and keeping track of the latest trends and projects that improve the performance, maintainability and scalability of web applications."

Brian Gottesman VP, Software Development Critical Mention

"Josh is a pleasure to work with and is always on top of his game. He has a vast knowledge of computer and internet related topics and always comes up with viable solutions to complex problems. I would recommend Josh to any other company seeking a dedicated employee."

Randall Amiel Internet Marketing Analyst Destination Rewards

PROFICIENCIES

Web UI Design

- Hand-coded HTML 4.01 & XHTML 1.0 (Strict)
- HTML 5
- CSS 1, 2,1 & 3
- Standards Compliancy
- Wireframing
- Designing & Implementing Accessible Web User Interfaces
- E-mail Design & Coding for Web & GUI Clients
- Search Engine Optimisation (SEO)
- · Cross-platform Compatibility
- Flash 8+
- AIAX
- Usability Studies

Beatrice Halstead

Marketing/Communications Specialist
Destination Rewards

"Josh is a creative and motivated

in the work force for 20 years. He

continually finds ways to implement

new concepts and existing concepts

in a more efficient fashion. Always

dedicated to the projects at hand and

making the best decisions to assist his coworkers and the companies needs.

I fully recommend adding Josh to any

team that requires growth, he will drive the project to fruition."

and professional presence is

team leader. [His] accomplishments

comparative to someone who has been

"Josh has been on several projects I have managed, and he was integral piece to the success of each project. He is great in a team environment, works great under pressure, and has an unbelievable knack for finding creative solutions for complex

Charlie Pfeiffer Project Manager Destination Rewards

requirements on projects."

"Josh ... exceeded all of my expectations. The quality of work was wonderful and Josh was inspired and energetic making him a pleasure to work with. The level of professionalism and expertise I encountered will keep me as a client for a long time to come."

Colleen Morneweck

Former Client
Owner of mybabysbows.com

Web Development

- JavaScript (jQuery / Prototype Frameworks, Backbone.JS)
- Ruby 1.8 and 1.9
- Ruby on Rails (Versions 1, 2, 3)
- Sinatra (for API development)
- Basic Understanding of Java / JSP Principles
- Git / GitHub (Preferred)
- CVS
- Subversion
- UNIX Shell Scripting
- MySQL 4+, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Redis
- XML / YAML / JSON (Preferred)
- RESTful API Design

System Administration

- Mac OS X Client / Server
- Microsoft Windows NT / 2000 / 2003 / XP / 7
- UNIX / Linux (CentOS, RedHat, Debian)
- FreeBSD 4/5
- Web Server Optimisation/Clustering
- cPanel / DirectAdmin / Plesk
- TCP / IP Networking
- BIND DNS Service
- FTP / WebDAV / rsync / SCP
- Apache / LigHTTPd / nginx
- Mongrel / thin
- Passenger / Ruby Enterprise Edition
- Sphinx Search
- Nagios & Zabbix Server Monitoring
- APF / BFD / SIM / Rkhunter (UNIX Security)
- Asterisk PBX / VolP
- VMware

Graphic Design/Other

- Adobe InDesign / Photoshop / Illustrator / Dreamweaver
- Minimal Flash experience (for API / widget cross-domain projects)
- Microsoft Office Suite
- Customer Relationship Management (CRM)

Code samples are available upon request.

Read more at: